<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ud01</title><link>https://cyanide4dinner.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on ud01</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Utkarsh Dwivedi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 12:40:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cyanide4dinner.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My First Post</title><link>https://cyanide4dinner.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 12:40:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://cyanide4dinner.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>Distractions Billions of dollars are invested and brightest specialists are hired each year to engineer new distractions. They fight for every second of our limited attention spans. Distraction is any activity that doesn&amp;rsquo;t directly append value to one or more of the pursuits one has priority to.
Still distractions can play a vital role if they are valuable in a secondary and indirect sense and not mind-numbing hedonistic activities. They can spark creativity, drive diverse learning and bring out unrealized observations, ultimately helping mold the person.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="distractions">Distractions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Billions of dollars are invested and brightest specialists are hired each year to engineer new distractions. They fight for every second of our limited attention spans.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Distraction is any activity that doesn&amp;rsquo;t directly append value to one or more of the pursuits one has priority to.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Still distractions can play a vital role if they are valuable in a secondary and indirect sense and not mind-numbing hedonistic activities. They can spark creativity, drive diverse learning and bring out unrealized observations, ultimately helping mold the person.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Yet, it is crucial to not dellude oneself in overdoing this, in the thinking that is helping when its excess only gives marginal returns.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Examples of current dominant distractions are -
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Media (Youtube, Twitch).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content (HackerNews, Reddit).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Social (Whataspp, Discord)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="solution">Solution&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Rejoice in idleness&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Not every waking moment is to be spent as part of some activity. For busyness is decpetive in making one think that productive work is taking place when one could be trekking on a wrong path all along.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be idle, allow boredom and find time to think, actually think. Let your mind wander, creativity take over. Direct your attention to solving problems instead of blindly copying someone else. Bring originality.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Limit consumption&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Allocate specific times for consumption.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consume only &lt;em>beneficial&lt;/em> media, discarding pleasures.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limit the time allocated for each.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Pursue&lt;/strong>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Spend more energy, attention and drive to bring the projects you&amp;rsquo;ve been working on to completion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stop being afraid, and tread boldly with weight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow yourself discomfort and suffering. Yet don&amp;rsquo;t hold back from giving 100% and some self-sacrifice.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>